Pedro Alerri

Almería, Spain • +34 619 96 76 52 • pedroagustinlecumberri@gmail.com • github

PROFILE

Experienced Image Specialist with a solid background in supporting media production teams across various commercial, editorial, and cinematic environments. I bring a diverse skill set, blending technical expertise in camera work, lighting, and picture editing with a strong problem-solving approach and core competencies including:

- Technical production for stills and moving image projects
- · On-set lighting and camera operation for commercials, TV, and feature films
- Image editing and picture archiving for commercial and editorial clients

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2020 - 2023 Freelance Photo Assistant

As a freelance photo assistant, I supported crews on various shoots by assisting with lighting, camera operation, and logistics by arranging, testing and operating equipment.

A portfolio is available here

2014 - 2020 London. Photo Assistant, Reserve Candidate (British Library), Photography Consultant (National Army Museum), Digital Operator and Assistant Picture Editor.

Companies: Gripvan, Metro broadcast, Pro lighting, LickerishLtd

I worked extensively in technical production for stills, moving images, and events across various roles. During this period, I contributed to the planning and executing of complex productions, managing lighting and camera operations. My responsibilities included optimising workflows, coordinating equipment logistics and providing on-set technical support to ensure seamless execution of small and large-scale projects.

I gained substantial experience managing photographic content including image editing and retouching in archiving-heritage environments, ensuring compliance with industry standards like IPTC. This period allowed me to refine my technical skills and deepen my understanding of the intricate balance between creativity and technical precision.

Archiving work examples: the Met Office, the House of Lords, Lickerish Ltd

2005 - 2013 Spain. Freelance Lighting cameraman, crew member

Camera operations and provision of technical assistance for major TV networks, (GoloboMedia, MediaPro, and Sogecable), focus puller (Warner Group) and lighting operator for major concert performances (Rolling Stones, Rod Stewart, U2, Lenny Kravitz)

SKILLS

- **Software**: Photoshop, Bridge, Capture One, Premiere, Figma, Sketch, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REACT
- Office Tools: Word, Excel, Acrobat
- Power, electrical dexterity, camera lighting photographic kit management and ops
- Other: Licensed driver, diver and sailor, English (C1), Spanish (native), communication to all levels

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

- 2024: Front-End Engineer. Codecademy & freeCodeCamp
- 2021: UX Designer. UX Design institute
- 2013: **MA in Philosophy**, University of Málaga, Spain

OTHER

UK Settled Status,